Animation Number 01
Animation Number 02
My story as Hanekawa Tsubasa
is not one that I can tell.
（羽川(はねかわ)）
羽川翼(つばさ)という私の物語を
is not one that I can tell.
しかし 私は
語ることができない
Animation Number 03
Am I      me?
What is         "me"?
Animation Number 03
Who        am I?
Who
Animation Number 03
am I?
What
Animation Number 03
am I?
The name "Hanekawa Tsubasa" is already very unstable.
（羽川）
そもそも 羽川翼という名前が
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Animation Number 6
既に不安定だ
My surname has changed several times already.
私は 幾度か 名字が変わっている
That's why I cannot seek a sense of identity in it.
だから 名前に
アイデンティティーを
求められないのである
None. Not at all.
少しも 全く
A large reason why I haven't been able to face myself till now,
これまで 私が
私と向き合ってこられなかった
大きな理由は
私が 自分の名前を
自分のものとして
is the fact that I did not acknowledge my name as something of my own.
認識していなかったから
なのかもしれない
So I should first learn my name.
ならば 私は まず
自分の名前を知るべきだ
Only then will I be able to define who I am for the first time.
それでこそ 初めて私は
私を定義できるだろう
This story is for you to learn that despite Araragi-kun's exaggerations about me being a saint
これは 阿良々木(あららぎ)くんが 大げさに
さながら 歴史上の聖人や
聖母のように語る私が
I am nothing more than just another human.
ただの一人の人間であることを
知ってもらうための物語だ
This is for you to know that I am a cat, a tiger, and a human.
私が猫であり 虎であることを
そして 人であることを
知ってもらうための
This is a story of betrayal for you all to become disappointed in me.
軒並み がっかりしてもらうための
裏切りの物語
Now, the time to awaken from the nightmare is here.
さあ 悪夢から目覚めるときが
やってきた
21st of August
Tsubasa Tiger          Part One
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Animation Number 37
The Hanekawa household's kitchen really has a lot of cooking utensils.
（羽川）
羽川家のキッチンには
調理器具が とにかく多い
What this signifies is that the three people living here each use their own utensils.
それが何を意味するかと言えば
この家に住んでいる３人が
それぞれ 別の調理器具を
使用しているということなのである
White rice     Express    Brown rice       Porridge
Timer       Keep warm
AM
PM
Thank you for this meal.
（羽川）いただきます
Animation Number 58
Animation Number 60
I finished my breakfast,
Animation Number 61
changed from my pajamas to my uniform,
Reference
Textbook
Dictionary
Animation Number 65
then I left home right away.
Emergency
Button
Sun Clothes Store
Oh   my
Animation Number 67
Animation Number 69
As I was walking, a twintailed girl
Animation Number 71
showed up.
Animation Number 73
Well, she didn't really "show up."
（八九寺(はちくじ)）あっ
Well, look at that.
（八九寺）これは これは
Animation Number 80
The girl: Hachikuji Mayoi
If it isn't Hanekawa-san!
羽川さんではありませんか！
It seems you're starting school today, Hanekawa-san?
今日から学校のようですね
羽川さん
That's right.
うん そうなんだ
To devote oneself to academics is another form of heavy labor.
学業に いそしむというのも
なみなみならぬ重労働ですよね
I'm still just in grade school,
かく言う私も
小学生の身ではありますが
but I've been devoting myself to overcome many troublesome obstacles.
数々の かん難辛苦を
乗り越えつつの日々に
身をやつしております
I see...
（羽川）へえ…
She doesn't
bite at all.
What are you doing, Mayoi-chan?
真宵(まよい)ちゃんは何してるの？
I forgot something at Araragi-san's house, so I wanted to get it back from him.
（八九寺）
阿良々木さんの家に
忘れ物をしてしまったので
それを返してもらおうと思いまして
（羽川）忘れ物？
Forgot something?
See?
ほら
He dragged me away last night. After that, I inadvertently forgot my backpack.
昨日 彼に連行されまして
その際に 私 うかつにも
リュックを忘れてしまったのです
Dragged?
連行？
Dragged against my will.
無理やり 連行されました
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That sounds more like a crime.
いや 犯罪性が増したけど
Animation Number 101
If I asked once more, "apprehension" might turn into "assault"
But can't you just go to Araragi-kun's house?
でも だったら 阿良々木くんの家に
行けばいいじゃない
（八九寺）
もちろん あの方の家には
最初に行きました
Of course that was the first place I went.
But it seemed he already left. His bicycle wasn't there.
でも 既に出られたあとのようで
自転車がありませんでした
Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh?
（八九寺）
あら？　あら？　あら？
Really?
へえ
If he left his house early in the morning, he might have had something really important before school,
もしも 早朝に家を出たというなら
学校に向かう前に
よっぽど重要な理由があるからか
or maybe it's already been taken care of,
あるいは 重要な理由は
あり終わっていて
Animation Number 107
Maybe he didn't
leave home early,
阿良々木くんは 昨日の夜から
ずっと帰っていないのか… かもね
and maybe Araragi-kun hasn't returned home at all since last night.
Animation Number 107
he hasn't yet
returned home?
Oh, I didn't think about that! As expected of Hanekawa-san.
わあ
その発想は ありませんでした
さすが羽川さん
私が阿良々木さんの家から
なんとか逃げ出したあと
Perhaps after I managed to escape from Araragi-san's house, some unavoidable catastrophe befell him.
あるいは 何か
のっぴきならない事件が
あったのかもしれません
（羽川）そうだね
Right.
I'm going to let the unavoidably disturbing phrase "managed to escape" slide here...
（羽川）
“なんとか逃げ出した”という
既に のっぴきならない—
物騒なフレーズは
スルーしておこう
Well, if I see Araragi-kun at school, I'll tell him you were looking for him, Mayoi-chan.
（羽川）
じゃあ 学校で
阿良々木くんに会ったら
真宵ちゃんが捜していたって
伝えておくね
Please do.
（八九寺）よろしくお願いします
Well then! I'll be seeing you again soon, Hanekawa-san!
（八九寺）
ではでは 近いうちに
また お会いしましょう 羽川さん
Yup! See you!
うん！　またね
My episode with him will be in the next title!
これから起こる
私と阿良々木さんのエピソードは
次回作で！
Stop the blatant foreshadowing.
露骨に伏線を張らないで
Animation Number 121
T
iger
Animation Number 135
Animation Number 137
Why am I not running away?
Animation Number 139
I'd be safe if I ran.
Animation Number 141
Why am I not running?
Animation Number 143
I
Hmm, so white.
（虎）うむ 白い
Aberration
Animation Number 147
So white... White lies of ignorance.
白くて 白々しい
Animation Number 155
But I am. White.
Animation Number 156
White—and crystal clear.
Animation Number 159
August 21                           Mon
（羽川）
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)さん 聞いて 聞いて
Senjougahara-san, listen up.
Naoetsu High
Naoetsu High School
On the way to school today, I met a tiger.
私 今日 学校に来る途中に
虎さんと出会っちゃった
That's nice.
（戦場ヶ原）あら そう
By the way, Hanekawa-san, am I obligated to listen to that story in detail?
ところで 羽川さん
私は その話を詳しく聞く義務が
あるのかしら？
Animation Number 161
detailed
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Was your "listen up" a serious plea instead of a mere preface?
“聞いて 聞いて”というのは
前置きじゃなくて マジなお願い？
Animation Number 162
Cat
Tiger
Animation Number 162
You said tiger, Hanekawa-san? Not a cat?
虎って言った？　羽川さん
猫じゃなくて？
A tiger, not a cat.
（羽川）うん 猫じゃなくて虎
Not a cat in tiger stripes?
（戦場ヶ原）
虎じまの猫じゃなくて？
Yup. A tiger in tiger stripes.
（羽川）うん 虎じまの虎
You saw a tiger. Don't you think that's a huge incident?
（戦場ヶ原）“虎を見た”って
それは 羽川さん
大変な事実じゃないの？
（羽川）
そう思うんだけど…
ああ でも 違うの
I do, but it's not like that.
It's not a tiger in real life. I think it's an aberration since it talked.
現実の虎さんじゃなくって
多分 怪異だと思うの
しゃべってたから
（戦場ヶ原）そういうことなら
In that case, I think you're better off talking to Araragi-kun than to me.
私よりも阿良々木くんに
相談したほうがいいと思うわよ
It's true I encountered a crab aberration before,
私は 確かに蟹(かに)の怪異に
出会ったことはあるけれど
Animation Number 175
and suffered quite a lot because of it too
but
but I don't know how to combat it, nor do I possess more knowledge than others.
それに対応する方法や
それに関する知識を
他人よりも持っているわけでは
ないのだから
But Araragi-kun seems to be absent today.
でも 阿良々木くん
今日は お休みみたいだし
え？　始業式の列の中に
いなかったっけ？　彼
He wasn't in line for the term's opening ceremony?
To go unnoticed when absent... That's even less of an existence than going unnoticed when you're there.
いないことに気付かれないとは
いることに気付かれない以上の
存在感のなさね
ウフフ
Animation Number 180
laughed she.
It made me shiver.
I met Mayoi-chan right before seeing that tiger this morning.
（羽川）
今朝 虎さんと出会う前に
真宵ちゃんにも会ったんだけど
あの子の話から推測すると
やっぱり 何かしているっぽいわ
From what she said, it seems he's up to something right now after all.
Something, huh?
何か… ね
Did you try calling or texting?
電話してみた？
それか メールとか
I've been hesitating.
（羽川）う〜ん はばかられて
I see. I think you can be a bit more impudent about things.
（戦場ヶ原）
そう 羽川さん
あなたは もう少し ずうずうしく
なっていいと思うけれど
Impudent?
（羽川）ずうずうしく？
Perhaps "audacious"?
（戦場ヶ原）ずぶとく… かしら
あの男は
あなたから頼られることを
That boy will never consider you relying on him bothersome, no matter what.
どんな状況でも
迷惑だなんて思わないわよ
You know this, right?
それくらい 分かってるでしょ？
う〜ん どうかな？
I'm not so sure.
Feasting
eyes
I guess I don't know that much.
あんまり分かってないかも
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（戦場ヶ原）
フウ…
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hanekawa-san, have you ever said "help me" to Araragi-kun?
羽川さん 阿良々木くんに
“助けて”って言ったことある？
えっ どうだろ？
I don't know. Probably not.
多分 ないんじゃないかな
I see. I haven't either. He helps us before we have the chance to.
（戦場ヶ原）そう　私もないわ
だって 彼は そう言う前に
私たちを助けてくれちゃうものね
Acting like a know-it-all, saying people just help themselves on their own.
“人は１人で勝手に
助かるだけ”とか
聞いたふうなことを言いながら
でも 何も言わなくても
助けてくれるからって
But I don't think it's all right to not say anything just because he helps us, without us saying a word.
何も言わなくてもいい
ということにはならないと思うのよ
What's that?
ん？　どういうこと？
Well, I was just thinking that perhaps you're expecting Araragi-kun to help you before you say anything.
いえ だから
ひょっとしたら 羽川さん
自分からは何も言わないうちに
阿良々木くんが助けてくれるのを
期待しているんじゃないか
って思って
Ah...
I think you can be honest and just rely on him. He's always wanted that.
素直に頼ってあげていいと思うわよ
彼は いつだって それを望んでいる
If you had been able to do that back during Golden Week...
昔 ゴールデンウィークに
あなたに それができていたら…
Should we head back?
（羽川）そろそろ 教室に戻ろっか
（戦場ヶ原）そうね
Sure.
I won't force you, but if something happens, don't think about trying to solve it alone.
無理強いはしないけれど
何かあったとき
１人で なんとかしようと
思っちゃダメよ
You have a strong tendency to, so if you don't want to trouble Araragi-kun, get me involved.
あなたは いまだに
その傾向が強いから
阿良々木くんに
迷惑をかけるのが嫌なら
私を巻き込んでちょうだい
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Let's see... I can die together with you at least.
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
そうね
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
一緒に死んであげることくらいは
できるわ
A fire.
火事だ
Animation Number 229
I said it.
My house is on fire.
私の家が火事だ
Animation Number 231
I called
that house
Animation Number 231
my own.
Animation Number 232
The house burning down was more shocking than I thought.
（羽川）
家が燃えるということが
思いのほか ショックだった
Enough for my mind to go completely blank.
頭の中が真っ白になるくらいの—
Animation Number 237
I was dumbfounded.
It was a devastating shock.
ひどい衝撃を受けた
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
With this, the Hanekawa family had its first conversation in a while.
この件で 羽川家は
久しぶりの家族の対話を
持つことになった
What was discussed this day was, "Where to sleep this evening?"
この日 話し合われたのは
“今晩 どこで寝るか”である
I said, "I'll be all right. I'll sleep over at a friend's place for a while."
私は“大丈夫だよ”
“しばらく 友達の家に
泊めてもらうから”と言った
My parents immediately consented.
両親は あっさり承諾した
Animation Number 243
100 yen
However, this put me in a tough spot. I'm probably completely unable to seek help from another person.
ただ 困ったことになった
多分 私は 自分以外の誰かに
助けを求めることができないのだ
Well, I'll be fine. Luckily I know where to go.
まあ 大丈夫か
幸いなことに 当てはあるし
Animation Number 247
And
that "where" is of course
Animation Number 247
the abandoned school we all know.
Animation Number 249
4th floor - the first classroom
Animation Number 251
4th floor - the second classroom
Animation Number 253
3rd floor - the first classroom
Animation Number 255
3rd floor - the second classroom
Thank you for this meal.
いただきます
Orange
water
Bis
cui
ts
I can use the school toilets and showers.
トイレやシャワーは
学校の設備を利用すればいいし
Standby
I can recharge my cell phone at school if I really need to.
携帯電話の充電も いざとなれば
学校で なんとかなるよね
I can study at the school library or the public library. The only other issue might be...
勉強は 図書室や図書館で
できるでしょう
あと 困ることといえば…
Animation Number 266
I was trying to make my thoughts coherent
even though I realized the contradiction.
Animation Number 266
So typical of me.
Thank you for that meal.
ごちそうさまでした
I can't say it was nice to sleep on,
（羽川）
寝心地がいいとまでは
さすがに言えないんだけれど
but strangely, I felt I slept more soundly than in the hallway at my house.
それでも不思議と 家の廊下よりは
安らかに眠れた気がする
Animation Number 273
Animation Number 274
Hmm, did I just skip a chapter?
（羽川）
ん？　章数が１つ
飛んでないかな？
Animation Number 274
気のせいかな？
まあ いいや
Animation Number 274
Is it just me? Oh well.
（羽川）んっ
（戦場ヶ原）羽川さん！
Hanekawa-san!
You're all right? You're alive?
大丈夫？　生きてる？
Huh? What? Good morning?
（羽川）あれ… あれ？　おはよう
You're all right?
大丈夫？
Y-Yeah...
Hand
You idiot!
（戦場ヶ原）バカ！
Idiot!
バカ！　バカ！
バカ！
Idiot!
Animation Number 303
It didn't hurt at all.
A-A girl sleeping all alone in a place like this!
お… 女の子が １人で
こんな所で寝泊まりして
何かあったら どうするの？
What would you have done if something had happened!
Animation Number 303
Yet it hurt a lot.
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
I apologized.
Animation Number 304
Animation Number 306
Or rather, I was forced to apologize.
No, I won't forgive you. I'll never forgive you.
（戦場ヶ原）
ダメよ　許さない
絶対に許さないんだから
I won't forgive you. Even if you apologize, I'll never forgive you.
許さない
謝っても 絶対に許さない
Yeah. I get it. I get it now.
（羽川）
うん 分かった　分かったから
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
Animation Number 311
Animation Number 312
I called you numerous times last night. But I couldn't get through at all.
（戦場ヶ原）
昨晩から 何度も
電話をかけていたのよ
でも 全然つながらなくて
Oh, sorry about that. I had turned it off.
（羽川）
ああ ごめん
電源を切ってたんだ
Because of that, I ended up running all over town.
（戦場ヶ原）
おかげで 私は 町じゅうを
駆け回ることになったのよ
I talked to all sorts of people and finally heard you were staying at a friend's house.
いろんな人に話を聞いて
どうやら 羽川さんは
友達の家に泊まっているらしい
という情報を入手して
But I didn't hear anyone say they had you over.
でも クラスの誰かが羽川さんを
泊めたって話は聞かなかったし
H-How many people did you talk to?
（羽川）
ど… どれだけの人に
話を聞いたの？
（戦場ヶ原）連絡網を回したわ
I set up a mailing group.
Or rather, I'm sorry. I met your parents, Hanekawa-san.
（戦場ヶ原）
というか ごめんなさい
羽川さんのご両親にも
会っちゃった
（羽川）えっ？　そっか
I see. So you met Father and Mother, Senjougahara-san?
戦場ヶ原さん
お父さんとお母さんに会ったんだ
I don't think you have to call people like that "Father" and "Mother," do you?
ああいう人たちを
お父さんとか お母さんとか
呼ぶことはないんじゃない？
Animation Number 323
said Senjougahara nonchalantly.
Quite nonchalantly.
It seems you've got a lot going on. I don't intend to pry though.
どうやら いろいろあるみたいね
詮索するつもりは ないけれど
Animation Number 326
And now for
something
completely
different
After that, I aimlessly searched around and finally thought of this place in the morning.
それから 闇雲に捜し回って
ようやく 今朝になって
ここに思い当たったのよ
Mitsüi Logistics
No, I thought of it from the start,
いえ 最初から
思い当たってはいたんだけれど
but I didn't want to think an adolescent girl could spend the night in a place like this.
まさか 年頃の女の子が
こんな廃虚で夜を過ごすなんて
考えたくはなかったから
So I thought, "Impossible. Most impossible of impossibles." That's why I looked here last.
まさかと思って
まさか まさかと思って
探索を最後に回したの
Animation Number 334
That's why I got so worked up that I even cried when I found you.
Th-Then could it be Senjougahara-san stayed up all night?
じゃあ 戦場ヶ原さん
ひょっとして 徹夜？
It's not "could it be." Senjougahara-san did.
（戦場ヶ原）
ひょっとしなくとも
戦場ヶ原さんは
Animation Number 336
After a sleepless night, everything's alright.
徹夜よ
I think it's also dangerous for a girl to run around the streets all night.
年頃の女の子が
夜の町を徘徊(はいかい)するのも
相当 デンジャラスだと
思うけど
Animation Number 338
Though to be correct that should be "all right."
I have no comeback for that.
（戦場ヶ原）
それを言われたら
返す言葉がないわ
I'm not the type who thinks things through much either.
私も あまり
後先考えるタイプじゃないからね
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Thank you.
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（羽川）
ありがとう
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's fine. It's something I did on my own.
（戦場ヶ原）
いいのよ
私が勝手にやったことだし
Looking at your state, it seems meddling got me nowhere.
その様子を見ると
空回りの
出過ぎたマネだったみたいだしね
That's not true.
（羽川）そんなことないよ
I finally realized just how dangerous what I did was after you told me.
言われて 自分が
どれくらい危険なことをしていたか
今になって ようやく分かった
火は人を狂わせるって言うけれど
It's said fire makes people crazy, so I think I was in a strange tense state from it.
私も 火事で
変なテンションになってたみたい
Well, you had that thing with the tiger too. I was a bit too worried about you.
（戦場ヶ原）
まあ 虎のこともあったしね
過剰に心配してしまったのは
どの道 確かだわ
Sorry to get all shaken up about you.
私としたことが
取り乱してしまって ごめんなさい
Well, shall we get going?
さあ それじゃあ 行きましょうか
Get going? Where? School?
行きましょうかって どこに？
学校？
My place.
私の家よ
I'll declare this up front. If you resist in any way,
あらかじめ 宣言しておくけれど
もしも 抵抗するようだったら
I'll shove a stapler in your mouth and staple your neck, if that's what it takes, Hanekawa-san.
口の中にホッチキスを突っ込んで
首筋に一撃 食らわしてでも
連れていくわよ 羽川さん
Animation Number 351
Animation Number 352
Father won't be home because of work, so you should stay the night.
（戦場ヶ原）
お父さんが
今日 仕事で帰ってこないから
Tamikura-sou
今日は泊まっていきなさい
羽川さん
Tamikura-sou
Hoshinomiya
2-4-101
Let's climb
the stairs
quietly
Let's climb
the stairs
quietly
Oh, it's all right?
（羽川）えっ いいの？
Actually, my parents won't be coming home tonight.
（戦場ヶ原）
実は今日ね 親 帰ってこないんだ
Why'd you rephrase it into a line from a romantic comedy?
（羽川）
なぜ ラブコメ風に言い直す？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Despite this, I once lived in a mansion.
（戦場ヶ原）
これでも 昔は
豪邸に住んでいたのだけれど
Back then, I could've easily tossed you into an extra room, but this is all I can do now.
そのころの私だったら
ポーンと ひと部屋
貸してあげられたのだけれど
今は これが精いっぱい
（羽川）ルパン風に言わないで
Don't say it like Lupin.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
This calms me down somehow.
（羽川）なんだか 落ち着くな
（戦場ヶ原）そう？
Really?
Something about this place feels good.
（羽川）なんか いい ここ
Almost feels like my own home.
自分の家みたい
（戦場ヶ原）ふ〜ん
In the first place, what is "my home" anyway?
（羽川）
そもそも 自分の家とは何だろう？
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hanekawa-san, you should stay home from school today. I'll stay home with you.
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さん
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
今日は 学校を休みなさい
私も休むから
Huh?
（羽川）え？
（戦場ヶ原）眠いのよ さすがに
I'm terribly sleepy, as expected.
Animation Number 376
The bed is waiting for us
I was into track, but it's been too long, so my legs and back are a mess.
元陸上部とはいえ
ブランクが長すぎるから
足腰もガッタガタだし
There's no way you slept well there, right?
羽川さんだって あんな場所で
安眠できたはずもないでしょう？
（羽川）
え？　そりゃまあ
そうかもしれないけれど
Well, um, I guess not...
And your bed head's awful.
寝癖も ひどいし
Don't talk about bed head!
寝癖のことは言わないで
But it's only the second day of the second semester. I can't possibly be absent from school.
でも ２学期も
まだ２日目だっていうのに
学校を休むわけには…
It's way more abnormal for a girl whose house burned down to cheerfully attend school the next day.
家が火事になった子が
次の日 普通に明るく元気に
学校に来るほうが
異常に決まっているじゃない
Things like that are why you're not street-smart.
そういうところが
世間ずれしてないっていうのよ
あなたは
You don't plan to go to college anyway, right?
大体 あなた 進学するつもりは
ないんでしょう？
Then you don't really have to worry about things like attendance or conduct.
だったら もう
出席日数とか内申書とか
そんなに気にすること
ないじゃない
Well, you're right, but...
（羽川）まあ そうなんだけど
Animation Number 387
But the rules...
I want to follow the rules.
Animation Number 387
Because they're rules.
That's enough. Rest.
（戦場ヶ原）いいから 休みなさい
If you must go to school, you need to defeat me first.
どうしても学校に行くというのなら
私を倒して行くことね
Sha kin~
シャキーン
Don't mouth off your own sound effects!
Animation Number 390
（羽川）
自分で効果音を
言わないで
Okay, okay. I'll do as you say today, Senjougahara-san.
分かった 分かった
今日は 戦場ヶ原さんの
言うとおりにするよ
To be honest, I do want to rest.
ゆっくり休みたいのも
正直 本当だしね
I'm glad you're forcing me.
そうやって強制してくれると
うれしいわ
（戦場ヶ原）だといいけれど
If you say so. It's not really like me to be a busybody.
こういう おせっかいって
あんまり 私向きじゃないし
But is it all right for you to be absent from school too?
（羽川）
あっ でもでも 戦場ヶ原さんは
学校 休んでも大丈夫なの？
（電話の呼び出し音）
（戦場ヶ原）う〜ん そうね
Well, let's see...
Calling
This is Senjou... Senjougahara.
（戦場ヶ原）オホッ オホッ
戦場ヶ… オホッ
戦場ヶ原です
I-It seems like I caught off-season influenza.
ど… どうやら 季節外れの
インフルエンザに
かかってしまったらしくって
Is it all right to go to school?
学校に行っても
大丈夫でしょうか？
ダメ？　残念です
I shouldn't? That's a shame. I really wanted to attend your class.
先生の授業を
本当に受けたかったのに
Then excuse me.
End call
There we go.
これでよし
Influenza? You didn't have to go that far. A common cold would've been fine.
インフルエンザって
なんで わざわざ
つかなくてもいいウソを…
普通に風邪でいいじゃない
Bigger lies are harder to catch.
（戦場ヶ原）
大きなウソのほうが
バレにくいのよ
（羽川）
ていうか そろそろ
服を着てくれないかしら
Could you put some clothes on already, Senjougahara-san?
戦場ヶ原さん
But I was going to take a shower.
（戦場ヶ原）
え？　でも私 これから
シャワーを浴びるつもりだし
Oh, I see.
（羽川）あっ そっか
You too right?
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さんも浴びるでしょ？
Yeah, I would like to. Of course you can go first.
（羽川）あっ うん　お借りするね
もちろん 戦場ヶ原さん
お先にどうぞ
Why are you treating me like a stranger? Let's take one together.
（戦場ヶ原）
何を水くさいことを
言っているの？
一緒に浴びましょうよ
We're both women. There's no shame in it.
（戦場ヶ原）
女同士なのだから
恥ずかしがることはないでしょう？
Wait, hold on a minute. No, longer! I sense a threatening atmosphere...
（羽川）
いや ちょっと待って
いやいや すごく待って
なんだか不穏な空気を感じるわ
Oh no. I have no ulterior motives.
（戦場ヶ原）
やあね　私に下心なんてないわよ
Or can't you trust your friends, Hanekawa-san?
それとも 羽川さん
友達が信じられないの？
I don't think I can trust a friend saying that in this situation.
この場面で その言葉を言う友達は
ちょっと信じられないかも
（戦場ヶ原）
誤解しないで
私は 神原(かんばる)とは違うのよ
Animation Number 409
The junior high Valhalla Combo
Don't get me wrong. I'm not like Kanbaru.
Animation Number 409
Kanbaru Suruga
I just want to see your naked body. I'm not planning anything beyond that.
私は 羽川さんの裸を見たいだけで
それ以上のことを
するつもりはないわ
Animation Number 411
Senjougahara's character was changing.
Please, Hanekawa-san, come take a shower with me!
お願いします 羽川さん
私と一緒に
シャワーを浴びてください
I guess it's all right. We're both girls, so it's not like I'm that opposed.
まあ いいか
確かに 女子同士で
そんな抵抗があるわけでもないし
Oh, I didn't expect you to agree. I did ask,
（戦場ヶ原）
あら 乗ってくるとは意外
誘っておいてなんだけれど
羽川さんて たとえ友達相手でも
そういう一線みたいなところは
but I thought you'd be someone who would never cross a line like that, even for friends.
絶対に越えない人だと
思っていたわ
What line? Like someone who won't let anyone in their room or never hangs out with anyone outside school?
（羽川）アハハッ　一線って何？
部屋に誰も入れない人とか
学校の外では誰とも遊ばない人とか
そんな感じ？
Yes.
（戦場ヶ原）そう
（羽川）否定はしないけどね
I won't deny that.
But it won't look good if I distance myself from the girl who slapped me while she was crying.
でも 泣きながら
私をたたいてくれた子を相手に
距離を取っても
今更 かっこつかないでしょ？
Who's that from?
（羽川）誰から？
Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）阿良々木くんから
Hmm, from what's written here, I think he sent it to you too.
ふむふむ　この内容なら
多分 羽川さんの携帯にも
同じメールが届いていると思うわよ
From: Araragi
No subject
I can't return home
for a while.
Don't vorry.
I can't return home
for a while.
Don't vorry.
Looks like Araragi-kun's up to something. And this time it looks pretty serious.
やっているようね 阿良々木くん
しかも 今回は かなり深刻と見える
I don't know much about spring break, but judging from these words, it looks as bad as then, if not worse.
私は そのときのことを
よく知らないけれど
文面から判断する限り
これは春休みか それ以上って
感じかしら？
（羽川）やっぱり そう思う？
You think so too?
for a while.
Don't vorry.
Yes. But if he'd go out of his way to send texts like this, that's a sign of growth.
（戦場ヶ原）ええ　でも まあ
わざわざ こんなメールを
送ってくるようになった分だけ
成長は見えるかしら？
He used to only see what was in front of his eyes.
昔は 目の前のことしか
本当に見えない男だったからね
Animation Number 433
Is it related to Mayoi?
Right.
（羽川）
そうだね
Calling
No good. It won't go through.
（戦場ヶ原）
ダメね　電話をかけてみたけれど
つながらないわ
Standby
Charging
Well, he is a boy, so we shouldn't worry too much.
まっ あっちは男の子なんだし
そう心配しなくてもいいか
いいでしょう
All right. When he comes back, I'll just gloat that I took a shower with you.
帰ってきたら 羽川さんと一緒に
シャワーを浴びたという
自慢話を聞かせてやるわ
I don't think that kind of harassment will work.
（羽川）
嫌がらせに なってないと思うよ
Her body lines were like this, and it was like this over here. And such...
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さんの体のラインは
こ〜んな感じで
ここがこうなってて〜 とか
身振り手振りをやめて！
Stop gesturing it all out!
But now that means we have to handle the tiger here by ourselves.
（戦場ヶ原）
でも これで こっちの虎には
こっちで対応するしか
なくなった感じね
（羽川）虎？
Tiger?
But the tiger...
でも 虎って…
I thought the tiger might be the reason your house was on fire.
（戦場ヶ原）
ん？　ひょっとしたら 私は
その虎が火事の原因なんじゃと
思ったりしたんだけれど
But it wasn't? Do you know the exact cause?
違うの？
火事の原因は はっきりしてる？
No, I don't know the details of that yet...
（羽川）
いえ それは まだ分からなくて…
I don't know.
分からないわ
I see. I might be jumping to conclusions.
そう　じゃあ それも
私の先走りかもね
Animation Number 450
A hasty ex-runner. Get it?
Animation Number 452
The posed look on your face makes the joke even worse.
Now, Hanekawa-san, we should shower for Araragi-kun.
さあ 羽川さん
そろそろ 阿良々木くんの分まで
シャワーを浴びましょ
I don't think we need to do it for him.
（羽川）
彼の分まで浴びる必要は
ないと思うけど
I'll look over your naked body for Araragi-kun then.
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くんの分まで
羽川さんの裸体を 私が見るわ
Don't you mean for yourself?
Animation Number 454
（羽川）
それは せめて
戦場ヶ原さんの分
だけにして
Then let's be friendly and wash each other's breasts.
（戦場ヶ原）
じゃあ 仲良く
お胸の洗いっことか しましょうね
（羽川）ハア…
Don't you mean scrub each other's backs?
背中の流しっことかじゃないの？
Hanekawa-san...
（戦場ヶ原）ねえ 羽川さん
While I eagerly stripped out of my uniform, Senjougahara-san suddenly inquired...
（羽川）
そそくさと制服を脱ぎ始めた私に
戦場ヶ原さんは 唐突に聞いてきた
Do you still love Araragi-kun?
阿良々木くんのこと 今でも好き？
Yup. I still love him.
今でも好きだよ
Animation Number 463
I answered without hesitation.
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）火憐だぜ！
（月火(つきひ)）月火だよ！
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
White Cat
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
（月火･火憐）
２人合わせて
“ファイヤーシスターズ”！
About time!
The Monogatari Series is back!
Somewhat scary
Pressure & expectations
2-cour run
（火憐）
お待ちどお
Finally, after going through Nisemonogatari and Nekomonogatari,
「偽(にせ)物語」「猫物語（黒）」をへて
we're leaving the spotlight to do the previews again!
ついに 私たちが
本編から予告編に帰ってきたぜ！
"Leaving the spotlight", sounds like we're being cast out...
You have to cheer up,
Fire Sisters!
Ah! Hanekawa-san?
（月火）
本編から予告編に帰ってきたって
出戻り感プラチナだけど
Tsukihi-chan, you idiot! We're no outcasts!
（火憐）
バカ！　月火ちゃん
出戻りとか言うな
Don't you bury us already!
Time to unleash
your imagination!
More Dreams!
More Passion!
副音声送りになりたいのか？
（月火）
副音声送り？
Berry juice?
Preview Quiz!
（火憐）予告編クイズ！
（月火）おっひさ〜！
Long time!
Together, we're the Fire Sisters. However...
（火憐）
私たちは ２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズですが
Ah! Try to stand on one foot
and behold our
dazzling imagination~
（月火）
ですが？
However?
What if we weren't together?
（火憐）
合わせなかったら
どうなるでしょう？
（月火）
それは個々人じゃないの？
Aren't we together right now?
Next Time! Nekomonogatari Shiro Episode 2!
Next Time
Tsubasa Tiger Part 2
（火憐･月火）
次回「猫物語（白）」
第２話「つばさタイガー其ノ貳(そのに)」
Tsubasa Tiger, Part 2.
What if we couldn't see each other anymore?
The cat tricked us!
But only a little
Meditating
Nyahahaha! Nyow take your time to think!
（火憐）
もしくは ２人合わなかったら
どうなるでしょう？
We would have to disband.
（月火）
解散だよ